

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Details

Eindhoven
Netherlands
+31 6 31950040
julio.schilders@gmail.com

Links

GitHub

Website

LinkedIn

Languages

English

Dutch

Hobbies

During my free time I like to learn new things and tinker on projects.

I also enjoy reading, teaching, listening to music and consuming entertainment.

Profile

I'm a social and passionate software engineer that's not afraid to ask questions. My strongest programming language is JavaScript, I'm most knowledgeable in React.

Technologies listed under professional experience are used by me personally.

Familiar technologies

(Programming) languages

JavaScript - TypeScript - Python - PHP - SQL - XML - HTML - CSS

Libraries & Frameworks

React - Next - Express - Electron - Angular - jQuery - Flask - Django - Laravel

Other tools

Git - Node - i18next - Docker - Webpack - Rollup - Gulp - Pug - Flow - Babel - AWS Sass - CSS Modules - Styled component

Professional experience

Front-end Engineer, Floorplanner, Rotterdam

OCTOBER 2019 - PRESENT

Floorplanner is an SaaS architectural visualization platform for drawing floorplans.

Technologies used: JavaScript - TypeScript - React - Node - PHP - Git - i18next Docker - Rollup - Gulp - Pug - Flow - Babel - Sass - CSS Modules - Styled components

- Worked on the Floorplanner Editor, Engine, Dashboard and a few websites.
- Maintained, tested, deployed and built some of the above mentioned products while continually reinforcing industry best practices.
- Responsible for implementing TypeScript in the codebase while refactoring many components and classes, removing dead code and fixing all found bugs on-the-go.
- Worked closely with the CEO and occasionally the CTO, to discuss and implement new marketable features.
- Effectively engineered and developed changes based on specific specifications.
- Applied and remained knowledgeable with existing and emerging technologies.

Lead Front-end Engineer, CodeCrashers, Eindhoven

JANUARY 2022 - PRESENT

CodeCrashers is an SaaS platform for viewing courses and handing in assignments.

Technologies used: JavaScript - React - Node - PHP - Laravel - Git - Webpack - Babel AWS - Sass - CSS Modules

- Responsible for the maintainability, integration, architecture and development of the Viewer and Dashboard while keeping technical depth to an absolute minimum.
- Worked closely with the CEO to discuss and implement new marketable features.
- Wrote a couple of courses and assignments that are being sold on the platform.

Education

HBO - Web development, REA, Eindhoven

SEPTEMBER 2018 - JULY 2020

MBO - Software development, Curio, Breda

AUGUST 2015 - JULY 2018